<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post-rsses on Markets, Mechanisms, Machines</title>
    <link>https://uvammm.github.io/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post-rsses on Markets, Mechanisms, Machines</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://uvammm.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 6: Experiments and False Findings</title>
      <link>https://uvammm.github.io/class6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvammm.github.io/class6/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;slides&#34;&gt;Slides&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dropbox.com/s/1qlxf5q1zo9a0qk/class6.pdf?dl=0&#34;&gt;Slides (PDF)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;schedule&#34;&gt;Schedule&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://uvammm.github.io/project2/&#34;&gt;Project 2&lt;/a&gt; is due Tuesday, 4 February (9:29am).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/uvammm/uvammm.github.io/blob/master/src/code/falsefindings.ipynb&#34;&gt;falsefindings.ipynb&lt;/a&gt; - Jupyter notebook on false findings&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Ioannidis. &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/article?id=10.1371/journal.pmed.0020124&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why Most Published Research Findings Are False&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. PLOS Medicine, August 2005.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ron Kohavi, Roger Longbotham, Dan Sommerfield, and Randal M. Henne (Microsoft). &lt;a href=&#34;https://uvammm.github.io/docs/controlledExperimentDMKD.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Controlled experiments on the web: survey and practical guide&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Data Mining Knowledge and Discovery, 2009.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office Hours Schedule</title>
      <link>https://uvammm.github.io/officehours/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvammm.github.io/officehours/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The office hours schedule is now set:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cameron Lloyd, Mondays, 6-7:30pm (Rice 442)&lt;br /&gt;
Denis Nekipelov, Tuesdays, 11am-12:30pm (Monroe 254)&lt;br /&gt;
Kyeongtak Do, Thursdays, 11am-12:30pm (Monroe Basement)&lt;br /&gt;
David Evans, Fridays, 8:30-10:00am (Rice 507)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t need to make an appointment for office hours - the point of
them is that you can just stop by and discuss whatever you want. If
you do want to meet with one of us but can&amp;rsquo;t make an office hours
time, best to send a message on slack to schedule another time (or for
me, you can use
&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidevans.youcanbook.me/&#34;&gt;https://davidevans.youcanbook.me/&lt;/a&gt;
to schedule it directly).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Survey Questions Answered</title>
      <link>https://uvammm.github.io/surveyquestions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvammm.github.io/surveyquestions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are my (Dave) answers to questions you asked for the &lt;em&gt;What
question do you have for us?&lt;/em&gt; question on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://uvammm.github.io/survey&#34;&gt;Beginning of
Semester Survey&lt;/a&gt;. If you missed your chance to ask a question
on the survey, or want to follow-up on any of these, feel free to ask
additional questions in slack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;question&#34;&gt;
What was the reason to start this course at UVA?
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;div class=&#34;answer&#34;&gt;
Prof. Nekipelov and I have a long-term goal of building a joint Economics/Computer Science major here, and this course is the pilot course for the major. I talked about my personal reasons for wanting to teach this course in &lt;a href=&#34;https://uvammm.github.io/class1&#34;&gt;Class 1&lt;/a&gt;.
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;question&#34;&gt;
Grading policy?
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;div class=&#34;answer&#34;&gt;
My main grading policy is to not have a grading policy. Policies are, by nature, rigid and inflexible, and at least for college students, grades shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be so stressful for you that you need a policy to be comfortable. Much better to not worry about them too much, trust your teachers to be fair, and focus on learning. I do have a grading &lt;em&gt;philosophy&lt;/em&gt;, which is roughly explained &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~evans/paradise/teaching/#grading&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;question&#34;&gt;
How did students from the previous semester decide what topics to focus on?
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;div class=&#34;answer&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way we ran the final project last year, students had about a week
to form a project team and come up with a project idea. We had some
time in class discussing project ideas and giving teams feedback on
their direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the teams came up with good ideas quickly. Others had a hard
time coming up with ideas, and we encouraged them to look for
potential projects based on their interests and things that bugged
them about their everyday lives. Some of these turned into interesting
projects, but others maybe not. (You can judge for yourself by &lt;a
href=&#34;/s19/finalreports/&#34;&gt;reading their final project reports&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think we&amp;rsquo;ll try a few more concrete things to find good project
ideas this semester, including having a list of suggested papers with
data sets as starting points. You&amp;rsquo;ll also have more time for the final
projects than last year&amp;rsquo;s course, so we hope everyone will find
someting exciting and interesting to do, and be able to execute a
fulfilling project.
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;question&#34;&gt; Assuming it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be directly
course related, I&amp;rsquo;m curious: What percentage of the value of a college
education would you estimate to be signaling?
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;div class=&#34;answer&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a good question, and in many ways, is course related (in some
ways, it is related to every one of your courses, of course, since
individual courses may have both signaling and intrinsic value). I
can&amp;rsquo;t give you a specific percentage, and I think it varies from -50%
(the value is learning, and the signal is actually harmful) to 100%
(the only value is signaling) depending on the degree and individual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bryan Caplan&amp;rsquo;s book &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Case-against-Education-System-Waste/dp/0691174652&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Case Against Education: Why the Education System
Is a Waste of Time and
Money&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
makes a very compelling case that nearly all of our current education
system is signaling (he does, thankfully, make at least a carve-out
exception for certain fields: &amp;ldquo;You obviously learn some valuable
skills in school (engineering, computer science, signaling models).&amp;rdquo;
(quoting David Autor).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a teacher, of course, I hope that things students learn and
experience in college can have a big positive impact on their lives,
and have seen at least some clear cases of evidence that this can be
true. That said, a large fraction of the value of a UVA degree is from
signaling, and the high success rate (however one might define
success) of UVA students after graduation has a lot more to do with
the filtering process done by admissions and the signaling value of
the degree, than what students learn here being so much better than
what students learn at a less prestigious school with lower success
rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite Bryan Caplan book is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Selfish-Reasons-Have-More-Kids/dp/0465028616/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Selfish Reasons to Have More Kids:
Why Being a Great Parent is Less Work and More Fun Than You
Think&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,
which I encourage everyone to read. Probably better not to read &lt;em&gt;The
Case Against Eduction&lt;/em&gt; until you are close to graduating with a
valuable (for signaling) degree, since part of the case he makes is
that while public investment in education is bad for society and
exaccerbates inequality, for a talented individual, investment (of
time and money) in education is unquestionably a great investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a course level, one (depressing to teachers) sign that UVA students
value courses more for than for learning is that my experience is
similar to Caplan&amp;rsquo;s &amp;mdash; although students will complain bitterly
about not being able to enroll in a class they want, I can count on
one hand the number of students (and on the other hand the
non-students) who have regularly attended and participated in classes
I&amp;rsquo;ve taught at UVA without getting being enrolled in them (despite
there being no barriers for any student to participate in any class
they want, regardless of whether or not they are enrolled and paying
tuition for it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;question&#34;&gt;
I am curious about the future of ad bidding, especially for large search engines like Google, Bing etc.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;answer&#34;&gt;
Me too! Luckily, Prof. Nekipelov will talk about this in several lectures (and you&#39;ll explore it in Project 4).
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;question&#34;&gt;
Does it matter what sort of computer we plan to use for this course?
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;div class=&#34;answer&#34;&gt;
No, other than it should be one that you are happy using and can use efficiently. The assignments will use Jupyter notebooks, which you can run on any computer with Python and a web browser, or using a cloud service.
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;question&#34;&gt;
Are groups from the first projects the same for the rest?
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;div class=&#34;answer&#34;&gt;
For the first two projects, we expect students to stay in the same teams. For later projects, you may be expected to mix up the teams.  Mainly, we want to make sure everyone is in a team with both Economists and Computer Scientists, and that all teams are working together well, and all individuals are contributing well to their team.
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;question&#34;&gt;
Would this class count for both a CS and Econ elective?
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;div class=&#34;answer&#34;&gt;
No, it can count as either, but not both. It depends on which of Econ 4730 or CS 4501 you are registered for.
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;question&#34;&gt;
What is the likelihood of getting into the class from the waitlist and will this course be offered at another time as well?
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;div class=&#34;answer&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone who can figure out the bureaucracy of getting added to the
class without the professors needing to use SIS will be able to join
the class. The is the only offering of the class this year. (As noted
above, anyone who doesn&amp;rsquo;t disrupt other students is welcome to
participate fully in the class regardless of whether or not you are
enrolled.  Being enrolled only impacts whether or not you&amp;rsquo;ll get the
credits for the class that may be useful for signaling.)&lt;br /&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;question&#34;&gt;
What sort of skills/intuition would you imagine a student should take from this class?
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;div class=&#34;answer&#34;&gt;
We hope everyone will gain an ability to approach problems from an
interdisciplinary perspective that combines Economics and Computer
Science. The specific skills that you&amp;rsquo;ll develop through the classes
and projects are less important than this, but we hope some of them
will be practically useful to you.
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;question&#34;&gt;
What do you think is the most beneficial yet overlooked aspect of this course?
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;div class=&#34;answer&#34;&gt;
Can&amp;rsquo;t say for this year yet, but last year the AKQ cookies were excellent!
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://uvammm.github.io/s19/images/cookies.jpg&#34; width=60%&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;question&#34;&gt;
If I am extremely beginner in terms of data science/econ, should I not take this class? What kind of CS practices will be involved?
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;div class=&#34;answer&#34;&gt;
We&amp;rsquo;re not expecting any background beyond what is listed as the
prerequisite for the course. We expect everyone to be comfortable at
least with small programs, so if you haven&amp;rsquo;t taken an introductory
computing course that was enough for you to be able to read and write
small programs, you should do that first. Otherwise, you have enough
computing background for this course, and you should benefit from
working in teams with more experienced CS students.
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;question&#34;&gt;
I don&amp;rsquo;t have a lot of econ knowledge and I&amp;rsquo;m afraid that I would have trouble understanding some of the materials.
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;div class=&#34;answer&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no expectation for the students in the CS section to have any
Economics background. We&amp;rsquo;ll try to remember this, but please do
interrupt in class with questions if we use any terms or concepts you
aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with. For the projects, our goal is that they will
require teams of students with Economics background and CS background
to work together, so you should make sure to ask the Econ students on
your team to explain things that you don&amp;rsquo;t understand (and conversely,
help explain CS things they may be unfamiliar with).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;question&#34;&gt;
How can we best protect our personal data and privacy?
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;div class=&#34;answer&#34;&gt;
Don&amp;rsquo;t give it up for free to &lt;a href=&#34;https://jeffersonswheel.org/google-federated-privacy-2019-the-dragon-in-the-room/&#34;&gt;companies with long track records for abusing it&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.virginia.edu/content/uva-engineering-school-student-probes-facebooks-vulnerabilities&#34;&gt;getting away with it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We plan to have a few classes in the second half of the class to talk
about more &lt;a
href=&#34;https://jeffersonswheel.org/usenix-security-symposium-2019/&#34;&gt;technical
aspects of privacy&lt;/a&gt;, and questions like how information can be
valued and incentives set up to encourage privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 4: Cost of Empirical Rick Minimization</title>
      <link>https://uvammm.github.io/class4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvammm.github.io/class4/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;slides&#34;&gt;Slides&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dropbox.com/s/j5u1grl8yiw7eqk/class4.pdf?dl=0&#34;&gt;Slides (PDF)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;schedule&#34;&gt;Schedule&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://uvammm.github.io/project2/&#34;&gt;Project 2&lt;/a&gt; is due Tuesday, 4 February (9:29am).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2</title>
      <link>https://uvammm.github.io/project2posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvammm.github.io/project2posted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://uvammm.github.io/project2/&#34;&gt;Project 2&lt;/a&gt; is now posted, and is due Tuesday, 4 February (9:29am).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Project 2, you will develop your model from &lt;a href=&#34;https://uvammm.github.io/project1/&#34;&gt;Project 1&lt;/a&gt;, with a goal of improving the the &amp;ldquo;Zestimate&amp;rdquo; residual error using the data for 2017 in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/c/zillow-prize-1&#34;&gt;Kaggle Zillow prize competition&lt;/a&gt;. The Kaggle competition has been concluded, so you&amp;rsquo;ll have to settle for learning, wisdom, and glory in place of Zillow&amp;rsquo;s $1.2M prize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will run a competition in class on February 4 to see which model
works best on a (secret until then) testing data set. You should
follow the spirit of this project, not try to cheat (for example, see
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theregister.co.uk/2020/01/21/ai_kaggle_contest_cheat/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;How a Kaggle Grandmaster cheated in $25,000 AI contest with hidden
code – and was fired from dream SV
job&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
- this is an extreme example of the kind of overfitting we talked
about &lt;a href=&#34;https://uvammm.github.io/class4&#34;&gt;last class&lt;/a&gt;). If you do discover a way to &amp;ldquo;cheat&amp;rdquo;, you can get
&amp;ldquo;bonus points&amp;rdquo; for this, but please don&amp;rsquo;t use it in the model you
submit for the competition.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 3: Introduction to Statistical Learning Theory</title>
      <link>https://uvammm.github.io/class3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvammm.github.io/class3/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;slides&#34;&gt;Slides&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://uvammm.github.io/docs/class3.pdf&#34;&gt;Slides (PDF)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 2: Why do we need causal inference?</title>
      <link>https://uvammm.github.io/class2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvammm.github.io/class2/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;slides&#34;&gt;Slides&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://uvammm.github.io/docs/class2.pdf&#34;&gt;Slides (PDF)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 1: Introduction, Causation</title>
      <link>https://uvammm.github.io/class1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvammm.github.io/class1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;schedule&#34;&gt;Schedule&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone wanting to be in the class should:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://forms.gle/5gmDkR5xnA6xFfst5&#34;&gt;MMM Pre-Semester Survey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join the &lt;a href=&#34;https://uvammm.slack.com/signup&#34;&gt;Course Slack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start forming a team for &lt;a href=&#34;https://uvammm.github.io/project1&#34;&gt;Project 1&lt;/a&gt; (you can use the &lt;code&gt;#teaming&lt;/code&gt; channel in slack to find teammates). Your team should be 2 Econ majors and 2 CS majors. (If you don&amp;rsquo;t find a full team, we will help form teams at Thursday&amp;rsquo;s class.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;slides&#34;&gt;Slides&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dropbox.com/s/2gv5p9152udfr0c/class1.pdf?dl=0&#34;&gt;Slides (PDF)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beginning of Semester Survey</title>
      <link>https://uvammm.github.io/survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvammm.github.io/survey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please submit this survey to register for the class:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://forms.gle/5gmDkR5xnA6xFfst5&#34;&gt;https://forms.gle/5gmDkR5xnA6xFfst5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(You should do this if you want to take the class, whether or not you are officially enrolled in it now.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://uvammm.github.io/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvammm.github.io/welcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the website for the joint Economics/Computer Science
course, &lt;em&gt;Markets, Mechanisms, and Machines&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More information will be posted here soon. For
now, you can get a rough idea what the course will be like by looking
at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://uvammm.github.io/s19&#34;&gt;Spring 2019 version of the course&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>