<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Markets, Mechanisms, Machines</title>
    <link>https://uvammm.github.io/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Markets, Mechanisms, Machines</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://uvammm.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule</title>
      <link>https://uvammm.github.io/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvammm.github.io/schedule/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;projects&#34;&gt;Projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday, 22 January:&lt;/strong&gt; Project 1: Warm-up, predictions from data&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday, 5 February:&lt;/strong&gt; Project 2: Housing market predictions&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday, 19 February:&lt;/strong&gt; Project 3: Stable matching&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Thursday, 7 March:&lt;/strong&gt; Project 4: Game theory auctions&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Thursday, 28 March:&lt;/strong&gt; Project 5&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-project&#34;&gt;Final Project&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday, 11 April:&lt;/strong&gt; Final Project Proposal&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday, 30 April:&lt;/strong&gt; Final Project Report and Presentation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;preliminary-readings-schedule&#34;&gt;Preliminary Readings Schedule&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is all tentative, and subject to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Week 1:&lt;/b&gt; Causal inference: concepts, models and tools
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Causal inference vs. prediction. Treatment effects. Treatment effects in
heterogeneous population. Endogeneity and instrumental
variables. Measuring consumer responses and ROI on advertising as
treatment effect. Other notions of causality: Granger causality and
Pearl&amp;rsquo;s idea of causality.
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Reading:&lt;/b&gt; Rubin, Donald B. &amp;ldquo;Causal inference using potential outcomes:
Design, modeling, decisions.&amp;rdquo; Journal of the American Statistical
Association 100.469 (2005): 322-331.&lt;br&gt;
Blake, Thomas, Chris Nosko, and Steven Tadelis. &amp;ldquo;Consumer heterogeneity
and paid search effectiveness: A large-scale field experiment.&amp;rdquo;
Econometrica 83.1 (2015): 155-174.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Week 2:&lt;/b&gt; Machine learning and prediction
&lt;blockquote&gt;
The concept of the learning machine and the concept of risk
minimization. Empirical risk minimization. Types of problems of
Statistical learning theory: pattern recognition, regression and density
estimation. Examples and properties of common algorithms for statistical
learning. Click prediction algorithms, Google&amp;rsquo;s DoubleClick and AdSense.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Reading:&lt;/b&gt; Vapnik, Vladimir. The nature of statistical learning
theory. Springer science &amp;amp; business media, 2013. (Chapter 1)
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Weeks 3-4:&lt;/b&gt; Matching problems
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Introduction to graph theory. Directed and undirected graphs. Graph
degree. Paths and cycles on graphs. Sorting and searching
algorithms. Tree graphs. Matching on bipartite graphs. Common algorithms
for matching on bipartite graphs.
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Reading:&lt;/b&gt; Norman L. Biggs, &amp;ldquo;Discrete Mathematics&amp;rdquo;, Oxford University
Press. (Chapters 15-17)
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Weeks 5-6:&lt;/b&gt; Competitive advertising markets
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Introduction to game theory. Games of complete information. Notion of
Nash equilibrium. Games of incomplete information. Notion of Bayes-Nash
equilibrium. Discrete and continuous games. Auctions. Common types of
auctions by design of allocation and payment rules. Multi-unit
auctions. Auctions used for online advertising. Generalized second price
auction and Vickrey-Clarke-Groves mechanism. Recent developments in
online advertising auctions.
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Reading:&lt;/b&gt; Gibbons, Robert. Game theory for applied economists. Princeton
University Press, 1992. (Chapters 1 and 3)&lt;br&gt;
M. Gentry, T. Hubbard, D. Nekipelov, H. Paarsch, &amp;ldquo;Structural
Econometrics of Auctions&amp;rdquo;. MIT Press
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Week 7:&lt;/b&gt; From Game theory to Algorithmic Game Theory
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Approximating best responses and utility guarantees. Possibility (and
impossibility) of implementation of Nash equilibria. Approximating Nash
equilibria.
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Reading:&lt;/b&gt; Jason Hartline, &amp;ldquo;Mechanism Design and Approximation&amp;rdquo;.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonhartline.com/MDnA&#34;&gt;http://jasonhartline.com/MDnA&lt;/a&gt; (Chapter 1)
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Week 8:&lt;/b&gt; Introduction to Economics of Information
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Informational content of Nash equilibria. Competition and user
information. Information and user privacy. Resent evidence on behavioral
response (and non-response) to changes in privacy.
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Reading:&lt;/b&gt; Hal Varian, &amp;ldquo;Economics of Information Technology&amp;rdquo;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://people.ischool.berkeley.edu/~hal/Papers/mattioli/mattioli.html&#34;&gt;http://people.ischool.berkeley.edu/~hal/Papers/mattioli/mattioli.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Tucker, Catherine E. &amp;ldquo;The economics of advertising and privacy&amp;rdquo;. International journal of Industrial organization 30.3 (2012): 326-329.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Week 9:&lt;/b&gt; Formal concepts of privacy
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Privacy and privacy threats. Risk of disclosure and a concept of
adversarial attacks. K-anonymity and related concepts. Analyzing
K-anonymous data. Differential privacy. Differential privacy and
robustness. Differential privacy and Machine learning.
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Reading:&lt;/b&gt; Lambert, Diane. &amp;ldquo;Measures of disclosure risk and harm.&amp;rdquo; Journal
of Official Statistics 9.2 (1993): 313.&lt;Br&gt;
Dwork, Cynthia. &amp;ldquo;Differential privacy: A survey of results.&amp;rdquo;
International Conference on Theory and Applications of Models of
Computation. Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg, 2008.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Week 10-11:&lt;/b&gt; Cryptography and data protection
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Week 12:&lt;/b&gt; Privacy-aware mechanism design
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Differential privacy as condition on strategic responses of
agents. Differentially private prediction of user choices. Designing
mechanisms with formal privacy guarantees.
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Reading:&lt;/b&gt; Nissim, Kobbi, Claudio Orlandi, and Rann
Smorodinsky. &amp;ldquo;Privacy-aware mechanism design.&amp;rdquo; Proceedings of the 13th
ACM Conference on Electronic Commerce. ACM, 2012.&lt;br&gt;
Dwork, Cynthia, and Aaron Roth. &amp;ldquo;The algorithmic foundations of
differential privacy.&amp;rdquo; (Chapter 10)
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>https://uvammm.github.io/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvammm.github.io/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div class=&#34;printing&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://uvammm.github.io/docs/syllabus.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF for Printing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CS 4501/ECON 4559: &lt;em&gt;Markets, Mechanisms, and Machines&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
University of Virginia, Spring 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meetings:&lt;/strong&gt; Tuesdays and Thursdays, 9:30-10:45AM, MEC 213.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intructors:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://people.virginia.edu/~dn4w/&#34;&gt;Denis Nekipelov&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans&#34;&gt;David Evans&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/strong&gt; Computer Science majors should register for the CS
4501 course, which has CS 2150 as a prerequisite. Economics majors
should register for the ECON 4559 course, which has ECON 3010 or 3110
and ECON 3720 or 4720 as a prerequisite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communication:&lt;/strong&gt; Course materials will be posted on the course
  website: &lt;a href=&#34;https://uvammm.github.io&#34;&gt;https://uvammm.github.io&lt;/a&gt;. We
  will use slack
  (&lt;a href=&#34;https://uvammm.slack.com&#34;&gt;https://uvammm.slack.com&lt;/a&gt;) for most
  communications with the class, and encourage you to use it for
  asking questions and discussions with the course staff and your
  classmates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
This is a draft syllabus, subject to change until the official syllabus is posted and distributed on the first day of class.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;course-description&#34;&gt;Course Description&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many modern systems that were designed to help people ranging from
Internet search platforms to car navigation or restaurant recommendation
apps rely on learning from its user past behavior to improve future user
experience. They use these past data to make inferences regarding the
choices that users will make in the future. The building blocks of these
system include Machine Learning tools for prediction, Econometrics
techniques to identify what causes humans to make particular choices and
algorithms from Computer Science to provide fast and efficient matchings
between users and their choices. Users in these systems can interact
with each other that requires concepts from Game Theory to analyze their
behavior and be able to forecast the evolution of these systems in the
short and long run. Finally, users may care about how exactly these
systems use and exploit their personal information to make those
predictions and inferences. The analysis of user privacy combines the
concepts from Economics of Information and formal privacy concepts from
Computer Science Theory while concepts from Cryptography can be used to
design systems that are protected from privacy breaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This course will present a collection of topics from Economics and
Computer Science that constitute the building blocks of modern
user-facing electronic systems. Many examples will come from modern
digital advertising platforms that have both created huge success in
user reach and effectiveness for advertisers and, at the same time, have
generated a trail user privacy concerns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;assignments&#34;&gt;Assignments&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main assignments for the class will be a series of projects where
students will work in small teams to analyze data from real electronic
platforms (e.g.,&lt;a
href=&#34;https://webscope.sandbox.yahoo.com/&#34;&gt;Yahoo!&amp;rsquo;s Webscope
data&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zillow.com/research/data/&#34;&gt;Zillow&amp;rsquo;s housing market data&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.census.gov/data.html&#34;&gt;data from the United States Census&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most assignments, students will be grouped into teams of two or
four students, including students in both the CS and ECON sections of
the course in each team. The project teams and assignments will
emulate the work of real interdisciplinary teams at leading
companies. It will be the team&amp;rsquo;s responsibility to distribute the
tasks, communicate with each other and explain in the project report
what part of the project was completed by what team member.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the final project, students will have an opportunity to define
their own open-ended project to answer an interesting question about
the world using methods and techniques from the class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the project assignments, there will be reading
assignments and other preparation assignments for classes, and there
may be some individual problem sets or quizzes (we hope that these
will not be necessary, but will use them if it seems like they will be
helpful for improving engagement in the class, or if there are
students who are not contributing fully to team assignments).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;projects&#34;&gt;Projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The due dates for the projects are below.  Unless specified different,
projects will be due at the beginning of class on the due date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday, 22 January:&lt;/strong&gt; Project 1: Warm-up, predictions from data&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday, 5 February:&lt;/strong&gt; Project 2: Housing market predictions&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday, 19 February:&lt;/strong&gt; Project 3: Stable matching&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Thursday, 7 March:&lt;/strong&gt; Project 4: Game theory auctions&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Thursday, 28 March:&lt;/strong&gt; Project 5&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Thursday, 11 April:&lt;/strong&gt; Final Project Proposal&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday, 30 April:&lt;/strong&gt; Final Project Report and Presentation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;evaluation&#34;&gt;Evaluation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grading will be based primarily on your performance on project
assignments, with adjustments for outstanding contributions to the
class.  For team projects, everyone in a team will normally receive
the same grade, except in situations where there are problems or where
not all team members contribute fully to the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grades will be calculated with several different weightings, where
your grade is based primarily on whichever weighting results in the
highest score. The range of possible weightings is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project 1: 0-5%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project 2: 5-15%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project 3: 10-15%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project 4: 10-15%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project 5: 10-15%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final Project: 20-65%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Class Contribution: 0-25%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spend your energy focusing on what you are learning, instead of
worrying about your grade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;honor&#34;&gt;Honor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe strongly in the value of a &lt;em&gt;community of trust&lt;/em&gt;, and expect
all of the students in this class to contribute to strenghtening and
enhancing that community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a student at the University of Virginia, you are trusted to be
honorable and expected to behave in ways that merit that trust. We
take advantage of this trust to provide a better learning environment
for everyone.  The course will be better for everyone if everyone can
assume everyone else is trustworthy, and we start from the assumption
that all students at the university deserve to be trusted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most assignments in this course, you will be encouraged to discuss
ideas and work with others to develop your ideas, and often expected
to work in a team.  We expect you to be honest, fair, and respectful
with your teammates, and to contribute fully to your team to the best
of your ability.  We also expect you to notify the course staff if
there are any problems with your team, or if you have teammates that
are not behaving honorably.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will always be expected to credit any collaborators and properly
cite any resources you use. The honor expectations for each assignment
should be clearly stated and make it unambiguous what is and is not
permitted. If it is ever unclear what is considered acceptable on an
assignment, please check with the course staff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;expectations-and-accommodations&#34;&gt;Expectations and Accommodations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you anticipate any issues related to the format, materials, or
requirements of this course, please meet with one of the instructors
outside of class so we can explore potential options. Students with
disabilities may also wish to work with the Student Disability Access
Center to discuss a range of options to removing barriers in this
course, including official accommodations. Please visit their website
for information on this process and to apply for services online:
&lt;a href=&#34;sdac.studenthealth.virginia.edu&#34;&gt;sdac.studenthealth.virginia.edu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://uvammm.github.io/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvammm.github.io/welcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the website for the joint Computer Science/Economics
course, &lt;em&gt;Markets, Mechanisms, and Machines&lt;/em&gt;. More information will be posted here as the semester approaches. For now, you can see the draft &lt;a href=&#34;https://uvammm.github.io/syllabus&#34;&gt;Course Syllabus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>